<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><jornalType>
    <categoria tipo="europe">
        <noticia>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/06/17/europe/georgia-tbilisi-zoo-floods-death/index.html</url>
            <titulo>Escaped zoo tiger kills man in Tbilisi, Georgia</titulo>
            <highlights>A tiger remains missing, zoo administration says</highlights>
            <highlights>Hundreds of wild animals escaped after weekend flooding destroyed the zoo</highlights>
            <highlights>At least 19 people died in the floods and six remained missing as of Tuesday, reports say</highlights>
            <date>2015-06-17T14:26:46Z</date>
            <author>By Laura Smith-Spark and Eka Kadagishvili, CNN</author>
            <newstext>Tbilisi, Georgia (CNN)Police have shot and killed a white tiger that killed a man Wednesday in Tbilisi, Georgia, a Ministry of Internal Affairs representative said, after severe flooding allowed hundreds of wild animals to escape the city zoo.
The tiger attack happened at a warehouse in the city center. The animal had been unaccounted for since the weekend floods destroyed the zoo premises.
The man killed, who was 43, worked in a company based in the warehouse, the Ministry of Internal Affairs said. Doctors said he was attacked in the throat and died before reaching the hospital.
Experts are still searching the warehouse, the ministry said, adding that earlier reports that the tiger had injured a second man were unfounded.
The zoo administration said Wednesday that another tiger was still missing. It was unable to confirm if the creature was dead or had escaped alive.
Georgian Prime Minister Irakli Garibashvili apologized to the public, saying he had been misinformed by the zoo's management when he'd previously said there were no more dangerous animals on the run.
City residents were urged to stay indoors for their own safety in the immediate aftermath of the floods. Volunteers have since been helping city workers with the cleanup operation.

At least 19 people died in the flooding, according to Civil Georgia, a news website run by the nongovernmental organization United Nations Association of Georgia. Six more remained missing, it said Tuesday, citing the State Security and Crisis Management Council.
Meanwhile, the zoo lost about half of its 600 animals, including lions, tigers, bears and wolves, in the natural disaster.
Some animals have since been recaptured, Civil Georgia reported. Others died in the floods or have been killed by police as they scour the streets for escapees.
Russian state news outlet RT.com reported Wednesday that an African penguin had made it 60 kilometers (37 miles) downriver from Tbilisi before being caught alive in a dragnet on the border with Azerbaijan.
Video from the city showed a large crocodile being restrained by rescuers, as well as a hippopotamus standing in floodwaters, looking confused.
The latter was eventually cornered in a city square before being tranquilized and recaptured. One terrified bear escaped the flood by perching on a window ledge.
Video footage also showed devastation across swaths of the Georgian capital, where flash floods swept away roads, at least one house and many trees. The corpses of dead animals could be seen amid the wreckage.

The problems began before midnight Saturday when heavy rainfall turned the Vere River, usually little more than a stream through the center of Tbilisi, into a raging torrent, according to Civil Georgia.
Images on Tbilisi City Hall's Facebook page showed roads washed out, hillsides collapsed and vehicles tossed about like toys. Rescue workers carried people on their shoulders through waist-high water.
Garibashvili extended his condolences Tuesday to the families of those killed in the flooding.
He also proposed the creation of a park in the zoo premises to honor those lost. "It will be a park of solidarity, a symbol of our unity, selflessness, and mutual support," he said in a statement on his website.
President Georgi Margvelashvili earlier said the capital's mayoral office would help those who had lost out financially as a result of the floods.
"The situation is difficult, but it can be handled except for the fact that we cannot bring back those who died," he said.
According to the World Wildlife Fund, as few as 3,200 tigers exist in the wild today.
Journalist Eka Kadagishvili reported from Tbilisi, and Laura Smith-Spark wrote from London. CNN's Kimberly Hutcherson contributed to this report.
</newstext>
            <videoURLS>
                <url>http://edition.cnn.com/videos/world/2015/06/16/zoo-animals-run-flood-tbilisi-georgia-erin-pkg-moos.cnn-ap</url>
                <caption>Flood causes zoo animal frenzy in Tbilisi 01:59</caption>
            </videoURLS>
            <videoURLS>
                <url>http://edition.cnn.com/videos/world/2015/06/15/georgia-floods-twelve-dead-chance-pkg.cnn</url>
                <caption>At least 12 dead, others missing in Georgia floods 01:26</caption>
            </videoURLS>
        </noticia>
        <noticia>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/06/16/europe/uk-syria-bradford-family/index.html</url>
            <titulo>Husbands of UK women feared to be in Syria plead for them to come home</titulo>
            <highlights>Husbands of missing women make tearful pleas for them to return</highlights>
            <highlights>A lawmaker says the women may be trying to join a brother who is in Syria</highlights>
            <highlights>The missing children are between 3 and 15 years old, police say</highlights>
            <date>2015-06-17T13:17:44Z</date>
            <author>By Laura Smith-Spark, Nic Robertson and Bharati Naik, CNN</author>
            <newstext>Bradford, England (CNN)The husbands of British sisters who have gone missing with their children pleaded tearfully Tuesday for their families to come home amid fears they have headed to Syria, which is ravaged by terrorism and war.
"You know, Mariya, I love you. I don't know what to say," said Akhtar Iqbal, the husband of Sugra Dawood, addressing his young daughter at a televised press conference in Britain. "I'm shaking and I miss you. It's been too many days. I don't where you are. Please come back home."
Then he teared up as he addressed his whole family, "I miss you, I love you, all of you. I love you a lot. I can't live without you. Please, please call me. "
Three sisters and their nine children from northern England disappeared while on a trip to the Middle East.
The husbands of two of the sisters appealed for help in tracking the family down amid concerns the sisters could be trying to join a brother in Syria.
"Please contact me," Mohammad Shoaib begged his wife, Khadija Dawood, at the press conference. "I am not angry. ... They are young kids, 7 and 5. And you know I love you so much."
The husband of the third sister did not appear, as he is not in the UK.
Balaal Khan, a lawyer acting for the Dawood family, said the three missing women and their children, ages 3 to 15, had traveled to Saudi Arabia on an Islamic pilgrimage on May 28.
But instead of returning home to the city of Bradford, in northern England, as expected Thursday, they disappeared.
They have not been in touch since June 9, and their cell phones have not been active, either. Nor have their social media profiles been updated in the past week, the statement said.
The sisters have been named as Khadija Dawood, Sugra Dawood and Zohra Dawood, all in their 30s.
Khadija Dawood's two children are Maryam Siddiqui, 7, and Muhammad Haseeb, 5; Sugra Dawood's five children are Junaid Ahmed Iqbal, Ibrahim Iqbal, Zaynab Iqbal, Mariya Iqbal and Ismaeel Iqbal, ages 15 to 3; and Zohra Dawood's two children are Haafiyah Binte Zubair, 8, and Nurah Binte Zubair, 5.
Khan, the lawyer, said all 12 boarded a flight from Medina, Saudi Arabia, to Istanbul on June 9. Early reports that two of the children failed to board the plane were wrong, he said.
The lawyer told journalists that there were no family problems and the husbands had no clue their wives were about to disappear. The families practice a moderate version of Islam, and there had been no indications of radicalization, he said.
He said that a trip to Syria was only one possible theory for the family's disappearance. But he mentioned, as well, that there were concerns about how the women had been able to buy tickets from Saudi Arabia to Turkey.

The brother of the three missing women is already in Syria, Naz Shah, a member of Parliament from the Bradford area, told CNN. And that is why the family is so concerned about the whereabouts of the missing women and their children, she said.
Shah added that she has "never heard of anything remotely like this in Bradford before."
Turkey has become a popular transit route for people seeking to reach Syria, where ISIS and other opposition groups have been battling the forces of Syrian President Bashar al-Assad.
Another local Bradford member of Parliament, Imran Hussain, has asked Britain's Foreign Office to help find the family.
The Foreign Office said: "We are in contact with West Yorkshire police and Turkish authorities and are ready to provide consular assistance."

The Dawood family reported the women and children's disappearance to police after they failed to return as expected.
Officers are investigating their whereabouts and are "working extensively with authorities overseas to try and locate them," a statement from West Yorkshire police said.
Assistant Chief Constable Russ Foster said: "We are extremely concerned for the safety of the family and would urge anyone with information to come forward and speak to us.
"Our priority is for their safe return; their families are gravely worried about them and want them home. One of our primary concerns is the safety and welfare of the young children."
News of the Dawoods' disappearance came shortly after family members of a teenage boy from West Yorkshire said they were "devastated and heartbroken" after ISIS released a photo showing the 17-year-old in front of an ISIS black flag. There are fears the boy, Talha Asmal from Dewsbury, may have been involved in ISIS suicide attacks near the Iraqi city of Baiji.
Other teens have also been swept up in the allure of ISIS. Earlier this year, three teenage British girls were seen on airport surveillance footage heading to Syria. A Scottish teenager wrote extensively on her Tumblr account about her love of ISIS. She stunned her family, left the country and became an ISIS bride and recruiter.
An American teenager from suburban Chicago, Mohammed Hamzah Khan, allegedly was on his way to join ISIS in October when he was stopped at an airport.
CNN's Nic Robertson and Bharati Naik reported from Bradford, while Laura Smith-Spark and CNN's Don Melvin wrote from London. CNN's Lindsay Isaac contributed to this report.
</newstext>
            <image>
                <url>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/150616152353-syria-uk-family-photo-super-169.jpg</url>
                <caption>In this family photo handout three of the children are seen outside an airport.</caption>
            </image>
            <videoURLS>
                <url>http://edition.cnn.com/videos/world/2015/06/16/fears-british-family-are-heading-to-syria.cnn</url>
                <caption>Fears missing British family are heading to Syria 01:20</caption>
            </videoURLS>
            <videoURLS>
                <url>http://edition.cnn.com/videos/tv/2015/03/11/how-isis-recruits-girls-and-women-to-jihad.cnni</url>
                <caption>How ISIS recruits girls and women to jihad 06:10</caption>
            </videoURLS>
        </noticia>
        <noticia>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/06/15/europe/freedom-project-misery-trail-children/index.html</url>
            <titulo>How children are trafficked into Europe</titulo>
            <highlights>CNN Freedom Project investigates human trafficking route from Africa to Europe</highlights>
            <highlights>Some boys who made treacherous trip die; others wish they had never left home</highlights>
            <highlights>Boys who found safety in Italy say there is an endless supply of other children dreaming of getting to Europe</highlights>
            <date>2015-06-16T15:05:53Z</date>
            <author>By Nima Elbagir, CNN</author>
            <newstext>Sicily, Italy (CNN)The 13-year-old boy looks off into the distance. He is slight of build with pale, almost yellowy eyes. When you see him you feel as if he has seen far too much already.
He is carrying a burden far too heavy for his age -- but despite his ordeal so far, smuggled across continents from Africa to Europe, and now living in a care home, his future could be far worse depending which route he takes next.
A CNN investigation spent months retracing the smuggling route from Egypt to Italy. Speaking to social workers and authorities, children and parents, there is evidence that many of the children were smuggled into Italy by the same criminal networks, who once they are in country, use them for illegal activities.
The Egyptian government agency charged with advising lawmakers on child protection matters told CNN that they believe in some cases the parents are guilty of trafficking, paying for their own vulnerable children to be smuggled so far from home in the hope of securing the family's future.
We were interviewing this Egyptian boy and his friends in the picturesque piazza of a small Sicilian town.
They came over to Italy together on an Egyptian smuggler ship. He was 12 at the time and crammed in with hundreds of others.
He says his parents paid 35,000 Egyptian pounds (about $4,500) for the privilege, never guessing what it would really be like -- tossed around for nine days, surrounded by vomit, and scared, uncertain what would meet them on shore.
I asked him what he would say to all the boys back at home, hoping to follow in his footsteps. He said he would warn them not to come but he also said he knew they wouldn't listen.
"Why would they? I didn't," he says. "Everyone does what their mind tells them. They won't take what we say."
I asked if, having suffered so much, he'd make the journey again? "What can I do? Yes. The burden back home is still the same."
Italian authorities say he is one of more than 1,000 young Egyptians sheltered in 100 Italian care homes now dotting the Sicilian countryside.
The cobbled streets and 17th Century architecture is a very long way from the Nile Delta villages many of the boys have come from.
I asked one of his friends if he calls his parents and what he tells them about their lives here, and if he's told them how close to death he came.
"I tell them nothing, just pleasantries and ask for their prayers. What difference would it make? They need me to make money."
These boys tell us their parents went in to debt to raise the fare for their crossing. They saw it as an investment in what they hope will be a better future for the whole family. The children are expected to find work as soon as they can and start sending money home.
Here at the care home, that's not possible so thousands of children are disappearing from the Italian social care networks.
Italy's Ministry of Labor told us almost 4,000 Egyptian children disappeared from the care system.
All the Italian authorities we spoke to who work with these children told us the pressure on the children would be unbearable even for an adult. They fear the consequences to their parents if the smugglers didn't get their money in full, or if the gamble doesn't pay off having sold what little of value they have.
The missing children can't work legally. Social workers tell us that too often the children turn to drugs, even prostitution, to get by.
Another boy we meet at the home asks me wistfully about Rome, which Italian authorities say is where so many of the disappeared head to.
I told him Rome is dangerous for children on their own, especially on the streets. I told him the stories we'd heard from the Egyptian teenagers we'd met in Rome -- the exploitation and the homesickness.
The Egyptian children in Rome tell stories of friends selling themselves on street corners -- but they sound suspiciously like they were speaking about themselves.
I told him it's better to do it all the legal way and better for him to get an education.
He listened politely until I'd finished then told me: "Better to be dead than useless."
Dominique Van Heerden, Luca Muzi, Sara Sirgany and Mohamed Kazaz contributed to this report.
</newstext>
            <videoURLS>
                <url>http://edition.cnn.com/videos/world/2015/06/15/elbagir-freedom-project-young-men-gone.cnn</url>
                <caption>Where have all the young men gone? 05:00</caption>
            </videoURLS>
        </noticia>
    </categoria>
    <categoria tipo="us">
        <noticia>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/06/17/us/new-york-prison-break/index.html</url>
            <titulo>New York prison break: Was husband warned about escape plan, murder plot?</titulo>
            <highlights>A source says Joyce Mitchell warned her husband about the escape plan</highlights>
            <highlights>Lyle Mitchell's attorney says the husband was kept in the dark</highlights>
            <highlights>Police say their search area is expanding based on information they've found</highlights>
            <date>2015-06-17T12:15:34Z</date>
            <author>By Randi Kaye, Catherine E. Shoichet and Jethro Mullen, CNN</author>
            <newstext>(CNN)His wife is accused of helping two convicted murderers break out of a New York prison. And the escape plan, a source says, also included a plot to kill him.
But how much did Lyle Mitchell know?
That's one of the multitude of questions investigators are asking as they search for the two fugitives, Richard Matt and David Sweat, in a massive manhunt that was expanding Wednesday.
A source with direct knowledge of the investigation told CNN that prison tailor shop instructor Joyce Mitchell knew the two inmates had plotted to kill her husband, told him about their plans to break out of the facility and warned him that his life could be in danger.
But a lawyer representing Lyle Mitchell said the husband, who also worked in the prison's tailoring block, was kept in the dark.
"He didn't know anything about the escape plan," attorney Peter Dumas said.

At this point, investigators don't believe Lyle Mitchell was involved in plotting the escape, the source with direct knowledge of the investigation said.
On Tuesday, Lyle Mitchell was face to face with his wife for the first time since her arrest last week. She's accused of sneaking hacksaw blades, chisels, drill bits, a punch and other contraband into the convicts' hands before they broke out.
The couple spent an hour together and were separated by glass, speaking over a phone in a private, unmonitored conversation, Clinton County Sheriff David Favro said.
Lyle Mitchell was supportive, and his wife seemed comforted by his visit -- the first she'd had since her arrest, the sheriff said.
"He's providing support," Dumas said. "He's not planning to testify on her behalf."
Joyce Mitchell's attorney, Stephen Johnston, said he did not know what the two talked about. He described his client's state of mind as "distraught, very weepy and very upset."
Dumas said Lyle Mitchell is also struggling to deal with what's happened and the revelation that "possibly there was a plan to do some harm to him."
"He's very confused. It's just a lot that's been thrown on his plate right now," Dumas said. "He's kind of reeling."
Clinton County District Attorney Andrew Wylie has not commented much on the husband, other than to say he's under investigation.
Investigators are looking at other prison employees as well and haven't ruled out that they may have played a role in the escape, the source with knowledge of the investigation said.

Officials are also investigating whether other inmates might have helped create some type of diversion before, during or after Matt and Sweat escaped, the source said.
Joyce Mitchell has pleaded not guilty to the two charges brought against her and has been talking to authorities. If convicted, she could face up to eight years behind bars.
Authorities are investigating whether the two inmates threatened Mitchell to force her to help, a New York state official briefed on the investigation told CNN. Investigators say they think Mitchell began getting cold feet about executing the plan but possibly had agreed to supply a getaway car because of threats to her and her husband, the official said.
But her relationship with the prisoners was years in the making, authorities said.
She'd been investigated in the past for an inappropriate relationship with Sweat that led corrections officials to move him out of the tailor shop in 2013 and keep them separated, said Wylie, the district attorney.
That's the year when she started having a sexual relationship with Matt, the source said.
The sexual relationship took place at the tailor shop in the Clinton Correctional Facility, the only known place the two were together, the source said.

With few clues pointing toward where Matt and Sweat went after they escaped, investigators are changing tack.
The search stretched into day 12 on Wednesday. The area that hundreds of law enforcement officers are combing is expanding, New York State Police said Tuesday evening.
Teams will be redeployed to new areas near the prison in Dannemora, New York, police said, saying the shifting search zone was based on information uncovered in the hunt for the fugitives.
"They've covered all the square footage over 10,000 acres, and covered it very well, so that we're confident that that area is cleared, and we're going to be moving on into a couple other areas that are fairly close to that search area just in case they are still here on foot," Favro, the Clinton County sheriff, told CNN's "New Day" on Wednesday.
More than 800 local, state and federal officers have been combing the dense woods and small towns in the area. Canine units are still searching for a scent that might lead police to Matt and Sweat, who escaped from the maximum-security facility known as "Little Siberia" in upstate New York on June 6.
"We're putting our heart and soul into this," Favro said of the search. "I'm confident that we'll be able to get these two."

But after earlier promising leads went cold, officials aren't even sure they're looking in the right place.
The fugitives could have made it across Lake Champlain to Vermont, and New York Gov. Andrew Cuomo has said he talked to his counterpart there to thrash out a "cooperative agreement" for the search.
Another possibility is Canada, whose border lies just 20 miles north of the prison.
But Jonathan Gilliam, a former FBI agent who has led manhunts, says the killers wouldn't try to drive past border checkpoints -- and going on foot through the thick woods is even harder.
"It's kind of a harsh environment, cold at night," he told CNN. "They're instantly setting themselves up for a fall."

Searchers are scouring parts of the Adirondacks in upstate New York, a 6 million-acre wilderness at the doorstep of the prison. It's filled with hundreds of cabins, many of them abandoned in the off-season.
Investigators think Matt and Sweat could be holed up in one of them. Or, they warn, the pair could invade a home and take hostages.
But Gilliam says that would be "a big chance to take."
"If you do that, even if you leave, now you've set a footprint for the police to latch onto," he said.

According to authorities, Joyce Mitchell says Matt and Sweat told her they planned to drive to an unspecified destination about seven hours away.
She backed out of the getaway plan, and it's unclear what other options the killers had in mind. But driving for that length of time at an average speed of 60 mph would put big cities like Boston, New York and Philadelphia within reach.
Those environments might be easier ones in which to disappear.
"People are very aware of who's around them" in small towns, said Gilliam. "They're very aware of what other people are doing. Once you get into a larger city, people just stop paying attention."

Even farther afield is Mexico, a possibility that Cuomo mentioned over the weekend.
The country, about 2,000 miles away, features in Matt's past.
In 1997, he murdered a man near Buffalo, New York, and then fled to Mexico, where he killed another man before being captured.
He had "Mexico Forever" tattooed on his back, police say.

Authorities are offering a $100,000 reward for information leading to the escaped inmates' arrests.
It's not clear how much money has been spent, but judging from the boots on the ground, it can't be cheap.
New York State Police say 1,200 leads have developed, but so far it's not clear whether any of them will pan out.
And time may be increasingly on the killers' side.
"You can't sustain this type of a manhunt for very long," Gilliam said. "It's just too much of a vacuum of all other resources."
Prison escape puts staff-inmate relationships in the spotlight
DA: Convicts may have rehearsed their escape route at night
Infamous manhunts: When police have tracked fugitives into the wild
CNN's Polo Sandoval, Alexandra Field, Eliott C. McLaughlin, Carolyn Sung, Shimon Prokupecz, Chris Welch, Carolyn Sung and Danelle Garcia contributed to this report.
</newstext>
            <videoURLS>
                <url>http://edition.cnn.com/videos/us/2015/06/17/joyce-mitchell-prison-break-plot-intv-kaye-ctn.cnn</url>
            </videoURLS>
            <videoURLS>
                <url>http://edition.cnn.com/videos/us/2015/06/16/joyce-mitchell-relationship-prison-escapee-field-dnt-newday.cnn</url>
                <caption>Source: Joyce Mitchell had sexual relationship with convict 01:54</caption>
            </videoURLS>
            <videoURLS>
                <url>http://edition.cnn.com/videos/tv/2015/06/17/exp-new-york-prison-break-manhunt-scenarios-sandoval-dnt-erin.cnn</url>
                <caption>Police surrounding new area in hunt for escaped killers 02:16</caption>
            </videoURLS>
        </noticia>
        <noticia>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/06/17/us/california-irish-students-balcony-collapse/index.html</url>
            <titulo>Families of Irish balcony collapse victims fly to California</titulo>
            <highlights>The fourth-floor balcony gave way during a 21st birthday celebration</highlights>
            <highlights>Five of the dead students were Irish and the sixth had dual Irish-U.S. nationality</highlights>
            <highlights>Books of condolence will be opened in Ireland, and flags will fly at half-staff</highlights>
            <date>2015-06-17T14:26:15Z</date>
            <author>By Eve Parish and Peter Taggart, CNN</author>
            <newstext>(CNN)The families of five Irish students who were killed when a fourth-floor balcony gave way beneath their feet began arriving in California on Wednesday to collect the remains of their loved ones.
Meanwhile, authorities have begun an investigation into the disaster, which took place early Tuesday at the Library Gardens Apartments in Berkeley as the students attended a 21st birthday celebration.
In all, six people -- all in their early 20s -- died after the balcony apparently separated from the wall of the building and overturned on top of the balcony below.
The five Irish students who died have been identified as Olivia Burke, Eoghan Culligan, Niccolai Schuster, Lorcan Miller and Eimear Walsh. They were all 21 years old and were in the United States on short-term work visas.
The sixth victim, Ashley Donohoe, 22, had dual U.S.-Irish nationality and was from Rohnert Park, California. She was Olivia Burke's cousin.
At least seven people were hospitalized Tuesday with serious injuries.
Ireland planned to fly flags over public buildings at half-staff on Wednesday to pay respect to the victims. A minute's silence will be observed in the Irish Parliament.
University College Dublin, where some of those who died were students, opened an online book of condolences.

"On behalf of the entire University community, I wish to extend our condolences to the families and friends of those who died and to those who were injured," said University College Dublin President Andrew Deeks.
"We cannot comprehend the desperate shock and grief they are feeling and we are heartbroken at their suffering and loss.
"Our students, like thousands of others across Ireland, head to the U.S. each summer on J1 visas to enjoy the experience.
"It is heartbreaking to imagine that such a tragedy would strike these wonderful students when their lives are opening up to discover the world."
He added that the University of California, Berkeley, had offered its counseling services to Irish students in the area.
A second book of condolences will be made available to sign in Dublin on Thursday.

Two of the dead, Schuster and Culligan, were former students at St. Mary's College, in Rathmines, Dublin, having graduated in 2012.
A notice on the college's homepage read: "The thoughts and prayers of everybody in the St. Mary's Community are with the families of Niccolai and Eoghan, and the other Irish youngsters who died or were injured in the heartbreaking accident in the United States yesterday.
"We also pray particularly for those being treated in hospital, and their families, many of whom are traveling today to the U.S."
Irish Foreign Minister Charlie Flanagan said a consular emergency line had received an "unprecedented volume" of calls Tuesday afternoon.
"This demonstrates that this is an incident that has touched many Irish families -- not just those whose sons and daughters were actually there, but all families who have a loved one traveling this summer," he said.
"Anyone with concerns about friends or family in the region should call the Emergency Consular Response Team on 353 1 418 0200."

</newstext>
            <videoURLS>
                <url>http://edition.cnn.com/videos/us/2015/06/16/deadly-california-balcony-collapse-bts.kgo</url>
                <caption>Irish consul: Very few remain untouched by this tragedy 01:49</caption>
            </videoURLS>
        </noticia>
        <noticia>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/06/17/us/nc-shark-attack-victim/index.html</url>
            <titulo>North Carolina shark attack victim: 'I didn't see it coming'</titulo>
            <highlights>Two teenagers lost lost their arms in Sunday's shark attacks</highlights>
            <highlights>The two attacks took place about 90 minutes apart</highlights>
            <date>2015-06-17T12:22:45Z</date>
            <newstext>(CNN)One of two North Carolina teens injured in a weekend shark attack said he had little warning of what was to come.
"I didn't see it coming," Hunter Treschl said from his bed at New Hanover Regional Medical Center in Wilmington.
"I was just in about waist-deep water, playing with my cousin ... and felt this kind of hit on my left leg ... like it was a big fish coming near you or something," the 16-year-old said in a series of videos released by the hospital.
"Then it just kind of hit my arm. That was the first I saw it, when it was biting up my left arm."

Hunter was one of two teens who lost their arms in the waters off Oak Island on Sunday. His arm was amputated below the shoulder.
Thirteen-year-old Kiersten Yow was the first swimmer attacked. She lost her arm at the elbow. The shark also bit her leg.
The two attacks took place about 90 minutes apart.
Kiersten's parents, Brian and Laurie Yow, said in a statement that their daughter was transferred from New Hanover to N.C. Children's Hospital in Chapel Hill on Monday, where"she remains in stable condition and is receiving excellent care."
Her road to recovery will be long and will include surgeries and rehabilitation, they said, "but her doctors at (the University of North Carolina) expect she will keep her leg and for that we are grateful."

To have two shark attacks so close together is extremely rare, one expert said.
"Having a series of injuries so close to each other in time and space makes this unusual," said George Burgess, an ichthyologist and fisheries biologist with the Florida Museum of Natural History. "It might suggest a single shark has been involved."
Only three times in the four decades that he's been studying sharks has Burgess seen attacks happen "so closely in time and space," he said. The other incidents occurred in Egypt and Florida.
Still Burgess said, shark attacks are unusual. Last year saw 72 attacks worldwide, only three of them were fatal. In a typical year, about four or five people are bitten by sharks on North Carolina beaches.
Shark attack kills woman in Maui

Hunter said he was working to stay positive.
"I've lost my arm obviously, so I have kind of two options," he said. "I can try to live my life the way I was and make an effort to do that even though I don't have an arm or I can kind of just let this be completely debilitating and bring my life down and ruin it."
Hunter said he chooses to "fight and live a normal life" despite losing his arm.
Messages of support have helped maintain his positive outlook.
"I've gotten a massive amount of messages from people all over who've wished me well," he said.
Hunter said he can't wait to get back home to Colorado Springs, Colorado, to see his friends.
Shark bites boy wading in waist-deep water in Florida

</newstext>
            <videoURLS>
                <url>http://edition.cnn.com/videos/us/2015/06/17/shark-attack-victim-speaks-dnt-pereira-newday.cnn</url>
            </videoURLS>
            <videoURLS>
                <url>http://edition.cnn.com/videos/world/2015/06/16/shark-attack-chances-odds-top-location-beaches-pictures-bpu-oirg.cnn</url>
                <caption>Know your shark attack stats 01:53</caption>
            </videoURLS>
        </noticia>
        <noticia>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/06/16/us/james-holmes-theater-shooting-fenton/index.html</url>
            <titulo>Psychiatrist: Holmes thought 3-4 times a day about killing</titulo>
            <highlights>Psychiatrist says she couldn't stop James Holmes from killing</highlights>
            <highlights>Dr. Lynne Fenton says he thought of killing people 3 to 4 times a day</highlights>
            <highlights>Holmes never talked about targets or specific plan to kill, Fenton says</highlights>
            <highlights>Holmes later mailed Fenton a notebook with detailed shooting plans</highlights>
            <date>2015-06-17T13:58:24Z</date>
            <author>By Ann O'Neill and Sara Weisfeldt, CNN</author>
            <newstext>Centennial, Colorado (CNN)A psychiatrist who treated James Holmes described him Tuesday as an anxious, anti-social oddball who thought obsessively about killing people in the months before he opened fire in a crowded movie theater in the Denver suburbs, killing 12 and wounding 70.
Dr. Lynne Fenton testified before a packed courtroom that Holmes told her in March 2012 that he had "homicidal thoughts" -- as often as three or four times a day. As his treatment progressed, he told her his obsession with killing was only getting worse.
And yet, Fenton told a jury there was little she could do because Holmes never talked about specifics. She couldn't place him under a psychiatric hold because he never disclosed his intention to kill -- even while he was acquiring weapons and "casing" a movie theater. And he never named a target, she testified.

Fenton, who headed the student mental health clinic at the University of Colorado's Anschutz Medical Campus, was perhaps the most anticipated witness at Holmes' capital murder trial. Courtroom spectators paid close attention as she testified on the 32nd day of a long and emotionally grueling courtroom drama.
Fenton testified that she treated Holmes from mid-March until June 11, when he left her care upon flunking out of his post-graduate course in neuroscience. He walked out of her office without saying goodbye or shaking her hand, she said.
Just over a month later -- on July 20, 2012 -- Holmes donned protective gear, tossed a tear gas canister into Theater 9 at the Century 16 multiplex in Aurora and shot into the audience at the midnight premiere of "The Dark Knight Rises."
He has pleaded not guilty by reason of insanity. If he is convicted of murder, prosecutors intend to seek the death penalty.
Fenton and the university are being sued by relatives of some of the victims, and she had never before spoken publicly about her seven meetings with Holmes.

Just hours before the attack, Holmes mailed Fenton a notebook containing elaborate sketches of the theater, details of his plans, and his rationale for carrying out the shootings. He later told a court-appointed psychiatrist that it was important for people to understand.
The notebook also contained Holmes' rambling thoughts about life, death and his "broken brain." He wrote that taking the lives of others would add value to his own life and keep him from committing suicide.
And yet, Fenton testified, Holmes never spoke of taking his own life during his sessions with her. Nor did he talk about feeling manic or depressed or about seeing "flickerings" or other hallucinations, as he did in the notebook. He focused on how social situations caused him great anxiety, mentioned a romantic breakup and repeatedly expressed his hatred toward humanity.
That dislike seemed to extend to her, Fenton said, and he did not volunteer information, responding to questions with terse, one-word answers. She said he was hostile and guarded and "wasn't very forthcoming." She suggested he might feel more comfortable with a male therapist, and brought a colleague into their later sessions.
Holmes had contacted the mental health clinic in mid-March, complaining of social anxiety. He was first seen by a social worker who described him as "one of the most anxious people she had ever seen."
Inside Holmes' "broken" mind

Fenton first saw him on March 21, and tentatively diagnosed him with "social anxiety" and obsessive-compulsive disorder. At their first meeting, Holmes expressed "thoughts about killing people," but Fenton said she didn't think he was dangerous. She believed his preoccupation with killing others was a symptom of obsessive-compulsive disorder.
During one session, she said, Holmes described homicide as "a solution to the biological problem," but added "you can't kill everyone, so it's not an effective solution."
Fenton said she focused on trying to build an "alliance" with Holmes so he would take his medication and keep coming back for counseling. She worried more that he would drop out of treatment, rather than carry out any plan to kill others.
But the diagnosis evolved over several sessions, and she later saw signs of paranoia and psychosis. She spoke with his mother and came to believe his homicidal thoughts were longstanding, dating back to childhood.
After their fourth session on April 17, she noted that he made several odd statements she didn't understand and wrote in her notes, "psychotic level thinking?" He said his homicidal obsession was "getting worse."
At that session, she wrote out a prescription using the name "Hughes" rather than "Holmes," which prompted him to send an email asking "an inconvenience, Fenton?" The memo field contained a strange emoticon, a variation of the letter Q. He later apologized for his "terrible mistake," stating that the emoticon represented a fist punching the psychiatrist in the eye.
"Violence, is that what you need to hear?" he asked, according to Fenton's testimony. She said she didn't fully understand what he meant, but added that he expressed concerned he would be "locked up."
Ex-girlfriend recounts how Holmes sent message about taking lives

In May, Holmes spoke of reading about the Unabomber and the "Tylenol terrorist." She learned that he had failed a course and would leave school. He said he could no longer afford treatment.
He seemed to have a plan, saying he had money in the bank, would get a job and could count on his parents for financial support.
"It sounded like he was functioning well and looking ahead to the future," Fenton testified. She added that he didn't seem depressed or angry and expressed "no thoughts of hurting himself."
By June 11, his last session, Holmes seemed to have developed more of an angry edge, and challenged her, saying she was afraid of him and didn't like him. Fenton did not call police, but she did get in touch with the campus threat assessment team. She also called Holmes' mother and learned he had been troubled for many years.
Fenton testified that she asked Holmes if he intended to act on his homicidal impulses, and he said he did not plan to take action. The notebook he mailed her told a different story.
"If the defendant had told you about buying weapons and making plans, would you have acted differently?" prosecutor George Brauchler asked.
"Yes," the psychiatrist responded, "it would have shown me he had a plan and intent, not just homicidal thoughts."
Prosecutors said they may finish their case by the end of the week.
Holmes told psychiatrist he has 'regrets' over shootings
CNN's Ana Cabrera contributed to this report.
</newstext>
            <videoURLS>
                <url>http://edition.cnn.com/videos/us/2015/06/10/james-holmes-trial-cabrera-orig.cnn</url>
            </videoURLS>
        </noticia>
        <noticia>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/06/17/us/nba-champion-golden-state-warriors/index.html</url>
            <titulo>Golden State Warriors down Cavaliers to win NBA title</titulo>
            <highlights>Andre Iguodala wins MVP award for the NBA Finals</highlights>
            <highlights>Golden State Warriors take NBA Finals, winning the final three games</highlights>
            <highlights>LeBron James scored 32 points for the Cavaliers</highlights>
            <date>2015-06-17T07:50:48Z</date>
            <author>By Steve Almasy, CNN</author>
            <newstext>(CNN)The Golden State Warriors won their first NBA title since 1975, downing the Cavaliers 105-97 Tuesday night in Cleveland.
The Warriors won the NBA Finals four games to two, winning the last three contests.
"They were all in it just to win," rookie coach Steve Kerr said of his players. "This is an amazing group of guys."
The four-time NBA champion Warriors were led Tuesday by Stephen Curry and Andre Iguodala, who each scored 25 points.
Iguodala, who started zero games during the regular season but was inserted into the first five during the Finals, was named MVP of the series.
"We are going to remember this for a long time," he said.
Golden State's Draymond Green had a triple-double with 16 points, 11 rebounds and 10 assists.
The Warriors won the game by hitting seven more three-pointers -- a margin that was larger until J.R. Smith hit four late, long-range shots -- and forcing the Cavs into 19 turnovers.
LeBron James topped the Cavaliers with 32 points, 18 rebounds and nine assists. Smith had 19 points, 15 in the fourth quarter.
"Our guys did more than anyone could expect to put themselves and to put our organization in the situation (where they played for a title)," Cleveland head coach David Blatt, also in his first NBA season, said. "Not every story has a happy ending; it doesn't mean it's a bad story. This was not. This was a good story."
The Warriors led 45-43 at halftime after Cleveland whittled away a 13-point deficit after the first period. James nearly had a double-double in the first 24 minutes, scoring 15 points and grabbing eight rebounds.
Golden State pounded on the Cavs early in the third and by the end of the period had a 12-point lead at 73-61. The Warriors went 13-0 during the NBA playoffs when they went into the fourth quarter with a lead.
The Warriors are one of three original NBA franchises still in existence. At first, they were based in Philadelphia, where they won the first NBA title in 1947 and one in 1956. Six years later they moved to the Bay Area when they were the San Francisco Warriors until 1971.
In 1975, the Warriors beat the Washington Bullets in the finals with four straight victories.

</newstext>
            <videoURLS>
                <url>http://edition.cnn.com/videos/sports/2015/06/17/golden-state-warriors-nba-champs-game-6-bts.nba-tv</url>
            </videoURLS>
        </noticia>
    </categoria>
    <categoria tipo="asia">
        <noticia>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/06/17/asia/china-south-china-sea-land-reclamation/index.html</url>
            <titulo>Beijing: Island building in South China Sea 'almost complete'</titulo>
            <highlights>China says land reclamation work in the South China Sea almost complete</highlights>
            <highlights>Government says it will continue construction work on the islands</highlights>
            <highlights>China is locked in a dispute with many of its neighbors over territory in the region</highlights>
            <date>2015-06-17T04:09:28Z</date>
            <author>By Katie Hunt and Vivian Kam, CNN</author>
            <newstext>Hong Kong (CNN)China's foreign ministry says it will soon complete controversial land reclamation on some islands and reefs in disputed waters in the South China Sea.
However, the ministry also said in a statement released Tuesday that it planned to build facilities on the artificial islands it has created and these would perform several tasks -- including military defense.
"According to the planned operation, China is about to complete the land reclamation operation at some of the Nansha islands where China has been stationed," the statement said. It did not give a time frame.
China has placed artillery pieces on one of its manufactured islands, the U.S. says, and China has announced plans for two lighthouses.

Last year, China stepped up land reclamation on several reefs in contested waters close to the Spratly Islands (called Nansha by China), alarming its Asian neighbors.
The United States says that China has reclaimed some 2,000 acres -- 1,500 football fields -- in the past 18 months and has called for an "immediate and lasting" halt to the island building.
In May, a U.S. surveillance plane carrying a CNN crew flew over some of China's artificial islands, triggered eight warnings from the Chinese navy to back off.
The South China Sea is the subject of numerous rival -- often messy -- territorial claims, with China, Brunei, Malaysia, the Philippines, Taiwan and Vietnam disputing sovereignty of several island chains and nearby waters.
The areas in dispute include fertile fishing grounds and potentially rich reserves of undersea natural resources.
China reiterated that its construction did not target any other countries or affect freedom of navigation by sea or air.
BEHIND THE SCENES: China's island buildup
CNN's Chieu Luu contributed to this report
</newstext>
            <image>
                <url>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/150514135956-south-china-sea-dispute-map-super-169.jpg</url>
            </image>
            <videoURLS>
                <url>http://edition.cnn.com/videos/politics/2015/05/20/south-china-sea-surveillance-plane-sciutto.cnn</url>
                <caption>High stakes surveillance over the South China Sea 03:47</caption>
            </videoURLS>
        </noticia>
        <noticia>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/05/11/asia/freedom-project-thailand-fishing-slave-ships/index.html</url>
            <titulo>Seafood from slavery: Can Thailand tackle the crisis in its fishing industry?</titulo>
            <highlights>Senasook worked for up to 20 hours a day in life-threatening conditions on a Thai fishing boat</highlights>
            <highlights>He suffered regular beatings from the ship's captain</highlights>
            <highlights>Rights groups estimate there could be up to 3,000 trafficked victims working on boats in these seas</highlights>
            <date>2015-05-17T13:46:14Z</date>
            <author>By Dean Irvine, Saima Mohsin, and Kocha Olarn, CNN</author>
            <newstext>Thai Prime Minister Prayuth Chan-ocha has told CNN that slave labor in his country's fishing industry "is now severe" and that Thailand will act to tackle it. CNN investigates the scale of the problem in this special report.
(CNN)The hours would be long and the work hard, but spending a year as a fisherman seemed like a good option to Samart Senasook.
Previous jobs as a security guard in Bangkok had been sporadic, so when a man known as Vee promised the 40-year old decent wages on a fishing boat he decided to take the chance.
Vee turned out to be a broker, a link in the chain of human trafficking that supplies the Thai fishing industry with thousands of migrant workers and turns many of them into virtual slaves.
Instead of a year on board a Thai fishing vessel, Senasook said he spent six, and was made to work 20-hour days in life-threatening conditions.
His unwanted odyssey only came to an end last month, thousands of miles from Thailand, on the eastern Indonesian island of Ambon.
The boat he was on was impounded by Indonesian authorities for suspected illegal fishing, with Senasook and his crewmates held in custody.

Looking back on his ordeal, that he says lasted from January 2009 to March 2015, Senasook rarely saw land, as the boat he was on roamed further and further from Thai waters in search of increasingly scarce fish.
Its catch was part of Thailand's multi-billion dollar seafood industry that feeds tens of millions in Europe and the United States.
Senasook describes his life on board as one full of intimidation, sleep deprivation and regular beatings from the boat's captain.
"(The captain) kicked and punched me," he said. "My nose and mouth were bleeding. I still have blood clotted in my teeth. My jaw hurts every time I chew."
With no way to escape, he became suicidal.
"I was thinking of my family, my mother. There were times, I was about to jump into the sea to kill myself.
"My friend from the engine room held me back. Otherwise I would have been dead by now," he said.
Senasook says the boat's captain kept his and the crew's ID at all times, essentially holding them captive.
When Senasook did finally get his hands on his identity card on Ambon, he was horrified to see it was in a false name. He had gone from being captive on board a fishing boat to being stranded on a distant island.
"There are many of my friends die in Indonesia. And their graves were with wrong names," said Senasook. "Like, if I died, at my grave it would not bear my name but it would be someone else."
In desperation, he wrote an open letter to the Thai Prime Minister asking for help. That helped to release him from Indonesian custody, but, isolated and penniless, he could not make his way home to Thailand.
He received a final payment of 1,750 baht ($53) from his ship's captain, but was then told he needed to pay 20,000 baht ($615) for the agent fee that brought him on the boat in 2009.

Eventually he received assistance from Thai-based Labor Rights Promotion Network (LPN) and was repatriated to Thailand last month.
He was one of the more fortunate ones. The LPN discovered a similar situation on the nearby island of Benjina, where the group says hundreds of other fishermen from across Southeast Asia were trapped and living in desperate conditions.
The rights group estimates there could be up to 3,000 trafficked victims working on boats in these seas.
"(The fishermen on Ambon and Benjina) have forged or no documents so can't return home," said the LPN's Patima Tangpratyakoon. "The situation is severe."
But the problem of modern day slaves fishing for seafood that ends up on dinner plates on the other side of the world goes much further than these tiny Indonesian islands.
The extent of the situation is hard to gauge. Thai government figures state that there are 145,000 working in its fishing industry, with 80% of those migrant workers, mainly from Myanmar, Cambodia and Laos. However, activist group Raks Thai Foundation suggests there are in excess of 200,000 trafficked, unregistered workers.
The exact number of fishing vessels is also unknown -- official figures put them at around 57,000 -- because registration is lax. The real number could be double that.

The issue of slavery and rights abuses in the Thai fishing industry has become acute in recent years. As the global demand for seafood has increased, the Thai economy improved, so attracting workers to dangerous jobs on fishing boats has become more difficult.
Last year the U.S. State Department downgraded Thailand to the lowest tier on its Trafficking in Persons Report 2014, which can result in the withdrawal of international aid.
Last month the European Union called Thailand a "non-cooperating" country because of poor monitoring and control of its fishing vessels and the trade of fish and seafood from other countries into Thailand.
Unless it cracks down on the situation, Thailand faces a financially damaging embargo on its fish exports to the EU from October.
In response, Thai Prime Minister Prayuth Chan-ocha has declared combating human trafficking a national priority.
In a statement in March, he called on all government agencies to "clean up their houses." Traffickers and government officials that have colluded with them "no longer have any room to exist in Thai society," he said.
According to Thailand's Department of Fisheries, new control measures are being implemented.
As well as inspections of fishing vessels, boats more than 30 tons in size that travel outside of Thai waters will have to be equipped with an electronic vessel monitoring system (VMS). Without it, the boats will not be given a fishing license. However, only around 6,000 boats in the Thai fishing fleet are of this size, according to the Marine Department.
Another new government initiative that came into play in April requires each fishing vessel to list who is on board, who it is licensed to, the name of its owner, and where it will operate before it leaves port and once it returns.
These "port-out, port-in" measures "will help enable us to reduce the risk of human trafficking, reduce the risk of force labor," said Warapon Prompol, deputy director-general, Department of Fisheries.
Crew manifests were not previously required.
"For the Marine Department we can check only a certain type of vessel, a certain size, too. But now the government is trying to reduce the size (of the vessel) that allows that we can check them," said Chula Sukmanop, director-general to the Marine Department.
He added that enforcement is made more difficult because all too often ships will change crew once they leave port.

While laws against human trafficking exist in the country -- a new Anti-Trafficking in Persons Act was approved as recently as March -- it has often been this lack of enforcement that has allowed exploitation of fishermen to continue.
"There have been laws that should penalize employers with penalties and not just the migrants themselves, but they've been rarely enforced in the past," said Max Tunon, senior program manager for the International Labour Organization, who specializes in migrant workers' rights in Southeast Asia.
"This is the most attention there's been on the issue, coming from the highest level," he added. "There's a greater acknowledgment that corruption exists and that increasing regulation (of the industry) needs to be linked to the broader issues of migration."
Exports by Thai seafood companies to the United States and Europe are worth around $2.5 billion annually, with Thai Union Frozen Products (TUF) one of the largest -- and owner of the John West and Chicken of the Sea brands.
In a statement in March, Khun Thiraphong Chansiri, TUF's president and CEO, called human trafficking in its supply chain "utterly unacceptable," but said "we all have to admit that it is difficult to ensure the Thai seafood industry's supply chain is 100% clean."
Progress to combat the problems of trafficked workers and slave labor has been made thanks to market and trade pressure, said Tunon. But it's still hard to see real change on the ground.
"It's been a challenge for years and it will be hard to measure progress because there has not been much of a baseline from which to gather credible information on the problem," said Tunon.
"The attention is now on the fishing industry, as it's particularly vulnerable, but this could help better protection for migrant workers in sections that don't have consumer or trade pressure, that aren't so visible because they don't feed into the global supply chain."

</newstext>
            <image>
                <url>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/150511110620-thai-fishermen-rescued-super-169.jpg</url>
                <caption>Fishermen board a Thai military plane in Ambon, Indonesia on April 9 during their repatriation.</caption>
            </image>
            <videoURLS>
                <url>http://edition.cnn.com/videos/world/2015/05/11/spc-pkg-mohsin-freedom-project-trapped-at-sea.cnn</url>
                <caption>CNN Freedom Project: Slavery at sea 05:13</caption>
            </videoURLS>
            <videoURLS>
                <url>http://edition.cnn.com/videos/world/2015/05/12/pkg-mohsin-cfp-thailand-fishing-slave-whitewash.cnn</url>
                <caption>Thai fishermen not recognized as trafficking victims 03:31</caption>
            </videoURLS>
            <videoURLS>
                <url>http://edition.cnn.com/videos/world/2015/05/13/spc-cfp-back-from-the-dead.cnn</url>
                <caption>Back from the dead -- Thai fishermen living as slaves. 04:48</caption>
            </videoURLS>
        </noticia>
        <noticia>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/06/16/asia/nepal-china-everest-quake/index.html</url>
            <titulo>China: Everest shifted 3 centimeters after Nepal quake but remains same height</titulo>
            <highlights>Chinese authorities say the magnitude-7.8 earthquake that devastated Nepal in April moved the mountain to the southwest</highlights>
            <highlights>Chinese state media says a satellite monitor on Everest has observed its movement since 2005</highlights>
            <highlights>It says the mountain has been moving northeast at a speed of 4 centimeters a year</highlights>
            <date>2015-06-17T09:26:27Z</date>
            <author>By CNN Staff</author>
            <newstext>(CNN)Mount Everest, the world's highest peak, was moved 3 centimeters (about 1.2 inches) southwest by the magnitude-7.8 earthquake that devastated Nepal in April, Chinese authorities say.
But the April 25 quake, which left more than 8,000 people dead, did not affect the height of the 8,848-meter (29,029-foot) mountain, according to the report by China's National Administration of Surveying, Mapping and Geoinformation.
Chinese state media reported the administration had set a satellite monitoring system on the peak in 2005 to observe the movement of the mountain.
In the decade since, Everest had been moving northeast at a speed of 4 centimeters a year, and had grown by 0.3 centimeters annually, state media reported.
The April earthquake reversed the direction of the mountain, shifting it to roughly where it would have been nine months earlier.
Nepal reopens 7 historic sites after quakes
It triggered a number of avalanches on and around the mountain -- which is at the border of Nepal and China -- claiming the lives of many climbers. The deaths led mountaineering companies to call off their climbs for the rest of the season.
Heroes' dreams 'scattered' by quake
New data showed a second deadly quake in Nepal, which struck on May 12 with a magnitude of 7.5, did not move the mountain, state media reported.
Previous analyses by seismologists have said that the mountain probably shifted by as much as meters in the quake, but the height was probably unchanged.
Teen climber survives deadly Everest avalanche

</newstext>
            <videoURLS>
                <url>http://edition.cnn.com/videos/world/2015/06/16/nepal-quake-shifts-mt-everest.cnn</url>
            </videoURLS>
        </noticia>
        <noticia>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/06/10/asia/china-pika-magic-rabbit-new-risk/index.html</url>
            <titulo>Fame poses new risk for China's 'magic rabbit'</titulo>
            <highlights>Few knew about China's "magic rabbit" until pictures went viral this year</highlights>
            <highlights>Rarer than a panda, it now faces a new threat: Human attention</highlights>
            <highlights>Man who discovered species says reserve is needed to protect tiny mammal</highlights>
            <date>2015-06-11T00:44:05Z</date>
            <author>By Shen Lu, CNN</author>
            <newstext>Beijing (CNN)Rarer than a panda, few people knew about the Ili pika until earlier this year when pictures of China's "magic bunny" went viral after being featured in a series of news reports.
But now the tiny and endangered mammal is finding out the price of fame.
Conservationist Li Weidong, who discovered the species in 1983, lamented the lack of funding for his conservation efforts when first interviewed by CNN in March.
READ: Meet China's 'magic rabbit'
He's since been able to raise almost $28,000 on a Chinese crowd-funding website, enough to fund his research and conservation efforts for the next year.
But Li told CNN this week that the tiny mammal now faces other threats.
People have tried to catch the pika, wanting one as a pet. Companies have offered Li funding to catch the pika and then artificially breed them, Li said.
"Ili pikas, as alpine animals, can't adapt to the environment at low elevations without special facilities," he said.
"Would they survive? Their population is already small enough. Human capture will accelerate the extinction."
Fearing that cameras might disturb pikas, Li said he has also turned away a dozen more photographers who hoped accompany him on his field research in the Tianshan mountains.

Native to the Xinjiang region of northwestern China, there are fewer than 1,000 of these creatures living in the Tianshan mountain range in the region, Li said.
Li discovered the pika, formally known as Ochotona iliensis, and named it after his hometown, Ili.
A year ago, Li spotted and photographed the elusive creature for the first time since the early 1990s. He estimates its numbers have declined by almost 70% since its discovery.
In 2008, the animal was listed as endangered by the International Union for Conservation of Nature but there's no official organization or team dedicated studying or protecting it, according to Li.
For years, Li has called for Ili Pika to be listed on China's List of Wildlife under Special State Protection -- part of the country's 1988 Wildlife Protection Law.
The appeal seems more urgent now as more people have laid eyes on the it, Li said.
Li said he is in negotiation with authorities in Jinghe County, where many Ili Pikas were discovered, for the establishment of a nature reserve to keep people away from the rare animals.

In late May, Li led a team of five volunteers to collect video footage from infrared cameras set up last August.
Some 30 infrared cameras captured about 16 video clips of the Pika from the two areas over the past 10 months.
Li said the video clips showed that pikas communicate with each other through their own urine traces and bodily waste.
"They can tell by sniffing whether another pika is nearby. If it is a member of the opposite sex, they find a mate. If it is within its own gender, they claim territory."
However, Li didn't find any pikas in the two sites where he spotted and photographed the elusive creature in July last year.
He said this doesn't mean there are fewer pikas now as footage from one more area is yet to be collected and the cameras only covered half of the census areas.
Yet it still worries him, he said.
"We don't know whether it's because the animals didn't come out during the winter, or they were eaten by natural enemies or they died."
To collect more accurate and complete information, Li said he plans to buy more infrared cameras with the recently raised money and set them up in all six areas.

</newstext>
            <image>
                <url>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/150323153926-china-ili-pika-1990-super-169.jpg</url>
                <caption>The last time Li managed to take a photograph of the rare animal was in 1990.</caption>
            </image>
        </noticia>
        <noticia>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/05/28/asia/china-space-mckenzie/index.html</url>
            <titulo>Chinese astronaut calls for cooperation, access to International Space Station</titulo>
            <highlights>CNN obtains exclusive interview with the three-person crew of the Shenzhou-10 mission</highlights>
            <highlights>Commander Nie Haisheng calls for greater international cooperation</highlights>
            <highlights>Analysts believe China's space program could become a world leader</highlights>
            <date>2015-05-29T03:21:08Z</date>
            <author>By David McKenzie, CNN</author>
            <newstext>"Inside Space City," a world exclusive CNN interview with three of China's top astronauts, premieres on Friday May 29 at 11:30 pm ET
Beijing (CNN)China wants greater cooperation with other nations in space, particularly the United States, the country's most experienced astronaut has told CNN in an exclusive interview.
Fifteen nations including the United States, Russia and Japan cooperate on International Space Station missions, but China's involvement has always been a non-starter because of longstanding resistance from U.S. legislators.
INTERACTIVE: IS CHINA WINNING THE SPACE RACE?
"As an astronaut, I have a strong desire to fly with astronauts from other countries. I also look forward to going to the International Space Station," Commander Nie Haisheng told CNN.
"...Space is a family affair, many countries are developing their space programs and China, as a big country, should make our own contributions in this field."
The comments came during a wide-ranging and exclusive interview with the three-person crew of the Shenzhou-10 mission inside Space City, the center of China's space program, near Beijing last month.
In 2011, Congress passed an act to bar NASA from having any bilateral contact with individuals of the Chinese space program because of national security fears.
"Every time it gets mentioned at all anywhere near Congress, it gets shut down immediately," space analyst Miles O'Brien told CNN.
"There is tremendous skepticism there about China. It is viewed as a foe, it is viewed as a government that seeks to take our intellectual property -- our national secrets and treasure."
In a white paper released Tuesday, China said that outer space had become an area of "strategic competition."
"The Chinese government has always advocated the peaceful use of outer space, it opposes space weaponization and an arms race in outer space. This position will not be changed," Wang Jin, a spokesman for the Ministry of Defense, said.
MORE: NASA astronaut: We risk losing out to China

A recent report for the U.S.-China Economic and Security Review Commission said China's improving space capabilities had "negative sum consequences for U.S. military security."
But Nie discounted those fears.
"The United States and Russia started their space programs early. They are the pioneers," he said.
He says foreign astronauts are welcome to visit China's own space station once it is launched.
The Chinese expect to finish their space station by 2022 -- around the time International Space Station runs out of funding, potentially leaving China as the only country with a permanent presence in space.
China launched its manned space program in 1992. It initially borrowed and bought a great deal of Russian technology, primarily by replicating their Soyuz space craft -- which they dubbed the Shenzhou.
But it has been steadily checking off the boxes in manned space flight. In 2003, it put its first man in space. In 2008, it completed its first space walk.
And in 2013 Nie and his crew completed the country's longest space mission to date and twice docked with the Tiangong-1 space lab.
MORE: Meet the crew of the Shenzhou-10

With support from the highest echelons of the ruling Chinese Communist Party and exceptionally deep pockets, most analysts believe China's space program could become a world leader.
"I think in the end -- tortoise versus hare style, they will probably win," said O'Brien.
In October last year, China launched its most ambitious unmanned space mission to date: to orbit the moon and then return to Earth.
Nicknamed "Xiaofei," or "Little Flyer" on Chinese social networks, the unmanned orbiter traversed 840,000 kilometers on its eight-day mission that saw it round the far side of the moon and take some incredible pictures of Earth and the moon together, the state-run Xinhua news agency reported.
It then successfully re-entered the Earth's atmosphere and parachuted down to the surface in Inner Mongolia.
Wu Yanhua, vice director of China's State Administration of Science, Technology and Industry for National Defense, said at the time the successful test mission has gathered a lot of experimental data and laid "a solid foundation for future missions."
While China hasn't committed to it, many analysts think it wants to put a man on the moon.
However, when asked, Commander Nie won't be drawn on whether this is the ultimate goal of the country's space program.
"For the next step, the focus is Tiangong-2 and then we will do more preparatory work for the space station."

</newstext>
            <videoURLS>
                <url>http://edition.cnn.com/videos/us/2015/05/28/inside-china-space-program-mckenzie-erin.cnn</url>
            </videoURLS>
            <videoURLS>
                <url>http://edition.cnn.com/videos/tv/2015/05/07/orig-china-space-race-history.cnn</url>
                <caption>China's 'Long March' into space 01:57</caption>
            </videoURLS>
            <videoURLS>
                <url>http://edition.cnn.com/videos/world/2015/05/12/pkg-mckenzie-china-simulation-room.cnn</url>
                <caption>How China's astronauts prepare for space 01:23</caption>
            </videoURLS>
        </noticia>
        <noticia>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/05/18/asia/china-families-belongings/index.html</url>
            <titulo>Stunning images show Chinese families and everything they own</titulo>
            <highlights>A Chinese photographer has spent a decade taking pictures of families and their entire belongings</highlights>
            <highlights>Most photos show a variety of landscapes and lifestyles, along with their neatly lined up possessions</highlights>
            <highlights>His goal is to tell the stories of those who have not been able to enjoy the success of China's economic boom</highlights>
            <date>2015-05-18T11:26:36Z</date>
            <author>By Shen Lu, CNN</author>
            <newstext>Beijing (CNN)For more than a decade, Chinese photographer Ma Hongjie has asked dozens of families across the country to empty their homes and pose in front of everything they own.
His goal is to tell the stories of those who have been bypassed by China's economic boom -- the people living on the bottom rung of society that haven't enjoyed the fruits of the country's transformation.
"The possessions are not even wealth. It's just their lives -- showing how the grassroots try to make a living," said Ma, a photo editor at Chinese National Geography magazine.
While the mesmerizing images show a variety of landscapes, lifestyles and cultures, what's most striking is their similarity -- the neatly lined up possessions are mostly daily essentials and tools of trade. Their owners appear proud yet humble.
Almost all of Ma's subjects are rural families. He has asked richer families living in cities to participate, but they weren't willing to take part in the project, he said.
They possess a lot more, and were afraid of the repercussions of showcasing their wealth, Ma explained.
"Yet grassroots were fully at ease showing me whatever they have," he said. "They'd first feel wary about my request, but when I showed the samples they thought it was interesting."
Although China now is the second largest economy after the United States, it is also home to the second largest number of poor people in the world, according to the World Bank.
Almost 100 million people lived below the national poverty line of $1 a day in 2012.

In his book, which is due to be published later in May, Ma gives the back stories of the families he's photographed.
The deepest impression the people he profiled has left upon him is their attitude. Powerless, they never demand anything, Ma said.
"Are they satisfied? No. But they have no choice but to accept whatever happens to them," he added. "But they try to live with however little they possess."
Although humbling, it also frustrated him.
"They suffer from silence."
Ma recently revisited the first family he profiled. They lived in a rural town in a mountainous area of Hunan province in southeastern China, back in 2003.
To his dismay, nothing had changed in the 10 years since his first visit; their shabby house had become even shabbier, he said.
Their sons wanted to get married, but the family couldn't afford to build new homes for them.
They had hoped tourism would develop in this old town so that the family would be subsidized for moving outthen the sons would be able to marry, he said.

Similar stories unfolded everywhere Ma traveled.
The Sun family live on boats on the Yellow River that winds through China's heartland. Sun Guiyou, who has been traversing the rivers and lakes for his entire life, says his biggest dream is to one day have a permanent house built on the land.
Although the family say they are better off since he first photographed them in 2006, nothing much has changed and they haven't been able to build a home on solid ground.
"The way they make a living doesn't change, they are still fishing," he said.
"The grandchildren didn't get a good education, or even dropped out of school. You can see them repeating their grandparent's life in the future."

Ma said he was stunned by the diversity of cultures and lifestyles he came across and that it was harrowing to witness these traditions erode.
Only a few of the local artisans and performers he met said their offspring were willing to carry on their crafts. Instead, they go to the cities and become migrant workers.
When he visited a village in Hainan province in 2010, people lived in small huts. On his return years later, the huts had been replaced by brick and cement dwellings built by the government.
In response, the villagers had built new huts next to the government subsidized housing instead, because they were not built in a way that suited their lifestyle. Ventilating smoke from how they cooked meals became difficult in those houses.
"The local government thought living in huts was uncivilized, but they were unique," Ma said. "Why should everything be uniform?"
The families he documented also shared a hatred of red tape - they bemoaned interference from the local government. So when the government decided to scrap an ancient tradition of taxing farmers for agricultural produce in 2006, farmers and peasants were thrilled by the news.
"They simply want to be left alone -- 'Don't make our life so troublesome, let us farm and let us live,' they told me." Ma said.

</newstext>
            <image>
                <url>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/150517112811-china-possessions-ma-hongjie-1-super-169.jpg</url>
                <caption>Long Yunping and his wife now live with their two sons and Long's 88-year-old mother in Huangsiqiao, Hunan Province. The family has an annual income of just over 3,000 yuan ($482). Their house, situated in an ancient village, was left to them by his father, and has a history of more than 100 years.</caption>
            </image>
            <image>
                <url>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/150517025651-china-possessions-ma-hongjie-5-super-169.jpg</url>
                <caption>The Sun family currently owns two large steel boats and two small wooden boats, which are worth more than 60,000 yuan altogether. Currently run a floating restaurant, and between this and fishing can bring in more than 30,000 yuan ($9,650) a year.</caption>
            </image>
            <image>
                <url>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/150517063333-china-possessions-ma-hongjie-22-super-169.jpg</url>
                <caption>Fu Naguo's family grows rice and sugar cane in Echa village, Dongfang city in Hainan Province. There only source of income is from selling wild berries they pick from the mountainside, making about 600 yuan ($96) per year.</caption>
            </image>
        </noticia>
        <noticia>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/05/19/asia/north-korean-child-defectors-revisited/index.html</url>
            <titulo>From traitors to poster children: Defectors 'forgiven' by North Korea</titulo>
            <highlights>Missionary couple helped hide young North Korean defectors in China</highlights>
            <highlights>They were caught and sent back, prompting fears for their lives</highlights>
            <highlights>Instead of punishment, the regime decided to send them to school and university</highlights>
            <date>2015-05-20T03:45:20Z</date>
            <author>Tim Schwarz, CNN</author>
            <newstext>Pyongyang, North Korea (CNN)Kkot-jebi -- literally "flower swallows" -- sounds poetic, but the reality is much harsher.
The North Korean term refers to homeless children, fending for themselves without the support of family or state. The word traces it roots back to the aftermath of the Korean War, an imaginative pronunciation of the Russian word "kochevyi," meaning "wandering," and referring to those displaced by the 1950-53 conflict.
During the 1990s, North Korea was hit by several years of famine as disastrous harvests laid waste to the land, killing hundreds of thousands, according to conservative estimates. The country's social safety net was reduced to tatters. Families fell apart. And flower swallows re-emerged in large numbers.
Although conditions today are much better, North Korea remains desperately poor. Food is in short supply for a large portion of the population -- and kkot-jebi are still very much in existence.

North Korea is one of the most secretive societies in the world. When a CNN team recently visited, our entire schedule was arranged by our official government hosts. Our "minders" accompanied us on every shoot. We had put in certain requests, but we never knew more than a few hours in advance what the next item on our itinerary would be.
When we were told to go to a meeting room at our hotel one afternoon, we had no idea who was going to be behind the doors, just something to do with the reality of defectors.
When we walked through the doors and saw eight young people sitting on one side of a huge round conference table, we immediately knew who we were to meet.

In early summer 2013, the world's media cried foul over the repatriation of a group of nine North Korea children, then aged between 14 and 19, from Laos. They had been picked up by border security as they were being smuggled from China into Laos by South Korean missionaries, in the hope of getting them resettled in South Korea.
READ: Agonizingly close to freedom
Pyongyang is not shy about its hatred of defectors. It refers to them in official media as "human scum" and accuses them of criminal acts, lying about their own country for fame and money and abandoning their own families.
The decision to return the children was widely condemned. Dire predictions were made about their fate: The children were being sent back to prison; they would face a lifetime of retribution and could even be executed.
But here in this room, nearly two years after their return, these former kkot-jebi appear transformed. Four young men dressed in the blue blazers of university students and two boys and two girls in secondary school uniforms, all sat waiting to answer our questions. The ninth member of the group was in a university further away from Pyongyang and could not be brought in at short notice.

They were all children between the ages of 12 and 17 when they crossed into China, separately or in small groups. They only met after they arrived at the missionaries' house.
We asked why they left -- it was an uncomfortable opening question.
"We were young," said 17-year-old Ri Gwang Hyok. "We just went to China for fun."
Pressed for more detail, Mun Chol, 21, admitted: "Frankly, we had some family difficulties. We had been through a period in our history we call 'the arduous march (the years of famine).' We were not living well. I was young and naive. We were living by the Amnok river, which is at the border. I meant to return home. I was curious."
We then asked how many of them had experienced hunger before they left.
Four of the eight raised their hands.
"It was winter. We had preserved food during autumn. But it wasn't enough. Our family was too large," explained Pak Kwang Hyok, 19.
Once in China, the children were brought to a house in the border town of Dandong, looked after by a South Korean missionary CNN has called M.J. in previous reports, along with his wife. There, according to M.J., the starving children were transformed. According to the youngsters now, the picture was not so rosy. They said they were kept in the house for a year and a half.
"The missionary lectured us about freedom," recalled Mun Chol. "But we weren't given any freedom. He forced us to study God and memorize religious books.
"Of course, the food was good," he added, "but that was our only pleasure. When you have food things seem OK, but a kid needs more than that."
Following our encounter with the students, CNN contacted M.J., who asked about their well-being. He says he misses them.
While hesitant to say much out of fear for their safety, he insists the students needed his help after fleeing North Korea.

China is a historical ally of North Korea, and North Koreans found illegally in the country face deportation if caught. After a year and a half, the missionary decided to move the children to a third country. He chose Laos, on China's southwestern border, from where he hoped he could get them to South Korea.
After a harrowing night trek for four hours through the hilly border region, the party were picked up by Laotian police and detained.
When they were told they would be sent back to North Korea they were terrified.
"The missionary said we would be killed if we went back," said Mun Chol. "He told us our families had been killed because we had left our homes."

But instead of being punished, they tell us they received special treatment, extra tuition to make up for three years of missed schooling, and are now studying in the best educational establishments in the capital.
"I was scared," admitted Pak Gwang Hyok. "I had left my home with a guilty conscience and spent time abroad. We had betrayed our country. I thought we would be punished. But now we are studying in the best universities in Pyongyang. Our fears were pretty foolish."
Soon after their return, the children appeared on North Korean television to denounce their enticement to defect by South Koreans. Now , more than a year later, they are again on display. They have become poster children for the "benevolence and forgiveness" of the North Korean authorities.
There is a huge difference between their lives when they left for China and now. "I feel like a pauper who has become a prince," said Ri Gwang Hyok.
But their families have not joined them in Pyongyang, the showcase capital. They remain in the poor border areas and their lives have not changed.
When he thinks about what might have happened if he had made it to South Korea, Mun Chol said, "If I had made it, I could have become a traitor -- a bad guy who deserts his family.
"I could have gone down in history as one of the 'scum of the earth.'"
READ: North Korean: I felt like a slave in Kuwait

</newstext>
            <image>
                <url>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/150519153722-north-korea-ri-quote-super-169.png</url>
            </image>
            <image>
                <url>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/150519153548-north-korea-mun-quote-super-169.png</url>
            </image>
            <image>
                <url>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/150519153632-north-korea-pak-quote-super-169.png</url>
            </image>
            <videoURLS>
                <url>http://edition.cnn.com/videos/world/2015/05/19/pkg-ripley-north-korea-defectors.cnn</url>
            </videoURLS>
            <videoURLS>
                <url>http://edition.cnn.com/videos/world/2013/09/30/north-korea-failed-escape-hancocks-pkg.cnn</url>
                <caption>Young North Korean defectors' nightmare 03:29</caption>
            </videoURLS>
            <videoURLS>
                <url>http://edition.cnn.com/videos/world/2015/05/08/pkg-ripley-north-korea-schools.cnn</url>
                <caption>North Korean kids taught devotion to the supreme leader 02:36</caption>
            </videoURLS>
            <videoURLS>
                <url>http://edition.cnn.com/videos/world/2014/10/17/pkg-mckenzie-north-korea-lifeline.cnn</url>
                <caption>The North Korea you aren't meant to see 02:19</caption>
            </videoURLS>
            <videoURLS>
                <url>http://edition.cnn.com/videos/world/2015/05/12/pkg-hancocks-north-korea-kim-jong-un-power.cnn</url>
                <caption>North Korean defector: Kim Jong Un out within 3 years 02:47</caption>
            </videoURLS>
        </noticia>
    </categoria>
    <categoria tipo="middleeast">
        <noticia>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/06/15/middleeast/egypt-suez-expansion/index.html</url>
            <titulo>Egypt hopes Suez Canal expansion will see cash flood in</titulo>
            <highlights>Egypt's President Abdel Fatah el-Sisi hopes facelifted Suez Canal will breathe new life into economy</highlights>
            <highlights>Canal earned $5.5 billion in 2014, which government hopes to increase to $13.5 billion by 2023</highlights>
            <date>2015-06-15T15:54:29Z</date>
            <author>By Ian Lee, CNN</author>
            <newstext>(CNN)It's arguably the most strategic waterway in the world. One that affects most lives on the planet. The Suez Canal may cut Africa off from Asia but it's a vital lifeline connecting the East and West.
Now Egypt's President Abdel Fatah el-Sisi hopes its facelift will breathe new life into Egypt's economy.
Everything about this project is ambitious. The funds needed for the new 70 kilometers of canal was raised within eight days. Only Egyptian citizens could invest in the project.
The President gave responsibility of completing the task to Vice Admiral Mohab Mameesh of the Suez Canal Authority. After consulting experts he concluded it would take five years to complete -- but that wasn't good enough.
"It would take five years, but we pushed and we made a pressure at the time and it will arrive in three years," Mameesh said. "But when [President el-Sisi] told me in one year, I said yes and changed all the plans."
Since the project began 10 months ago, 41,000 people have been working around the clock. They'll move a total of half a trillion cubic meters of earth -- equivalent to moving 200 Great Pyramids.
To help accomplish that task, Mameesh says he has employed 75% of the world's dredgers.
The goal is to turn this one-way canal into a two-lane highway. Currently, ships have to wait to be part of three convoys with room for only eight megaships per day.
Nearly 10% of all global maritime trade passes through the Suez Canal. That's 18,000 ships a year, a figure that Mameesh hopes the new canal will increase to 20,000.
The navigation time will be reduced from 22 hours to 11 hours meaning the latest must-have electronics from Asia will arrive sooner.

Last year, the canal earned roughly $5.5 billion, which the government hopes to increase to $13.5 billion by 2023. It's an ambitious projection when global trade increases at roughly 5% annually.
"The projected 13 billion are slated to come from passage fees and from the increase in number of ships but also efficiency and increase of maritime services presented to passing ships," says Mameesh.
The new canal is envisioned to be the cornerstone of Egypt's next grand industrial project that'll be situated along its shores. The government hopes it'll create $100 billion in revenue and produce 1 million jobs. How this will be accomplished is not entirely known, as details are scarce.
One potential roadblock to all of this is security.
Militants aligned with ISIS wage a deadly insurgency next to the canal in Northern Sinai. Hundreds of people have been killed in the fighting.
About two years ago, militants fired a rocket propelled grenade at a passing boat in the canal, but no one was killed in the attack.
Mameesh insists the boats are safe, with Egypt's military patrols helping to keep the roughly 100-mile (160 kilometer) canal secure.
But the admiral's most pressing concern is making the August deadline and bringing the 150-year-old canal into the 21st century.

</newstext>
            <videoURLS>
                <url>http://edition.cnn.com/videos/world/2015/06/15/ian-lee-egypt-set-to-open-new-suez-canal-in-august.cnn</url>
                <caption>Egypt set to open new Suez Canal in August 02:37</caption>
            </videoURLS>
        </noticia>
        <noticia>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/06/16/middleeast/egypt-court-morsy-sentence/index.html</url>
            <titulo>Egypt's Morsy: Death sentence upheld; life term in second case</titulo>
            <highlights>Muslim Brotherhood asks for international help to end what it calls Gen. Abdel Fattah el-Sisi's "cruel dictatorship"</highlights>
            <highlights>Ex-President Mohamed Morsy was sentenced last month for his role in 2011 prison break</highlights>
            <highlights>Three other senior members of Muslim Brotherhood also sentenced to death</highlights>
            <date>2015-06-16T14:41:24Z</date>
            <author>By Ian Lee, Jethro Mullen and Eve Parish, CNN</author>
            <newstext>Cairo (CNN)A court in Egypt upheld a death sentence Tuesday against former President Mohamed Morsy.
Morsy, 63, was sentenced to death last month for his role in a 2011 prison break.
Morsy, along with 16 other Muslim Brotherhood leaders, was also given a life sentence for espionage. Life in Egypt means 25 years.
Three more senior members of the organization -- Khairat Al Shater, Mohamed Beltagy and Ahmed Abdel Alaty -- were sentenced to death by hanging.
The political wing of the Muslim Brotherhood, the Freedom and Justice Party, called the decision "politicized" and the charges "fabricated."
"President Morsy's trial has fallen far below the most basic international legal standards," a statement from the Muslim Brotherhood said. "Today's announcement is another nail in the coffin for democracy in Egypt."
It called on the international community to stop what it called the "cruel dictatorship" of Gen. Abdel Fattah el-Sisi.
The military ousted Morsy, Egypt's first democratically elected leader, in 2013.
Opinion: The folly of Morsy's death sentence
CNN's Ian Lee reported from Cairo, and Jethro Mullen wrote from Hong Kong. CNN's Sarah Sirgany contributed to this report.
</newstext>
            <videoURLS>
                <url>http://edition.cnn.com/videos/world/2015/06/16/egypt-morsy-death-sentence-upheld-lee-lklv.cnn</url>
                <caption>Egyptian court upholds Morsy death sentence 03:37</caption>
            </videoURLS>
        </noticia>
        <noticia>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/06/09/middleeast/iraq-mosul-isis-takeover-anniversary/index.html</url>
            <titulo>Iraqi veteran who fled Mosul a year ago: ISIS will never, ever leave my city</titulo>
            <highlights>CNN's Ben Wedeman and his crew encounter an Iraqi who has seen it all -- war with Iran, invasion of Kuwait</highlights>
            <highlights>Louay Hikmat Shawkat thinks ISIS is permanently entrenched in Mosul</highlights>
            <highlights>Christian families tell CNN of the hardships they've suffered after being driven out of their beloved city</highlights>
            <date>2015-06-10T12:25:21Z</date>
            <author>By Ben Wedeman, CNN International Correspondent</author>
            <newstext>Baghdad (CNN)We had just finished up our shoot in Al-Makasib Girls' Elementary School in Baghdad's Saadoun neighbourhood and were loading the gear into the car when a man sitting in a wheelchair across the courtyard beckoned to me.
"Come, talk to me, too," he said.
He introduced himself as Louay Hikmat Shawkat, Iraqi Army veteran of the war with Iran and then the 1991 Kuwait war, refugee from Mosul and a self-described translator of English, French, "Canadian" and "Yugoslavian."
Given that the latter two aren't languages, and his English was a tad scratchy, I was intrigued.
We were visiting the school to talk to its current "residents" -- 48 Christian families who had fled Mosul when ISIS took over a year ago. Mosul, in northern Iraq and one of the nation's largest cities, is about 405 kilometers (about 250 miles) from the capital of Baghdad. But for these internal refugees, it might as well be a world away.
I asked Louay, who is 60, when he thought he might be able to return home.

"Take it out of your mind that ISIS is going to leave Mosul," he insisted, gesturing with his hand as if he were pulling a thread out of his head.
The chances he and his wife will someday return to their home in the Mosul suburb of Hamdaniya, he said, are "one in a hundred. One in a million!"
Louay said he suffers from diabetes, but he insists on lighting up another cigarette in his nicotine-stained fingers "because I get upset whenever I speak about "Da'ish", the Arabic acronym for ISIS.
ISIS, he said, "is an illness. It's impossible to cure. Cancer can be cured, tuberculosis can be cured. Almost every illness can be cured, but not this one."
His diabetes causes him to suffer from dizziness whenever he stands up. "If I were well," he vows, "I would go fight them myself."
Like everyone else I spoke with at the school, he is desperate to leave Iraq, but his attempts to apply for asylum have come to naught. His last hope, he told me with a mischievous grin, is an old Canadian girlfriend in Montreal.

In the school's makeshift kitchen, I met Linda Jannan, who was busy with the washing up.
She fled Mosul with her husband and three children in August, first going to Dohuk, in Iraqi Kurdistan, where they spent six months in a tent in a refugee camp.
A thin women in her 30s with the dark circles under her eyes, she also was desperate to leave Iraq.
"We are finished," she told me. "Our future, our children, our men have been destroyed. We're too afraid to go out and find work. If only someone outside Iraq will help us find a solution, let us emigrate. We have no hope left."
She and her husband had applied to asylum in the United States and Germany, but they were rejected because they have no close relatives in either country.
Obama: No 'complete strategy' yet on training Iraqis
Over the past few months, these refugees have been visited by a variety of reporters. And it's clear their patience is wearing thin.
"What's the point of all this talk?" one man asked me, after declining my request for an on-camera interview. "We talk, we talk, and nothing happens," he snapped.
Firyal Abdel Kareem, who was sharing the kitchen with Linda Jannan, is at her wits' end. She spent the winter months in a windy tent in Zakho, near the Turkish border, and is now suffering from Baghdad's sweltering summer heat.
"Find a solution for us," she told me, "it's enough. We are tired."
"Either they take us out of here, or send us home. Do we have to stay in this school, or in a tent?"

I've been covering Iraq since 1994. I covered the impact of the draconian international sanctions imposed on the country after Iraq's 1990 invasion of Kuwait. I covered the U.S.-led invasion in 2003 and the messy, bloody aftermath. And now I'm back covering the war against ISIS.
I'm lucky. I come and go as I please. For the people in this school, there is no such luxury. Thair Al-Naim, his wife and their three young sons left behind a relatively comfortable life in Mosul last summer. He's now penniless and out of work, all his construction equipment seized and sold by ISIS.
Speaking to him in the classroom they now call "home," I sense a deep weariness with a life that, for too long, has been fraught with violence and fear.
"Since the fall of Saddam," he sighs, "all we've had is war after war, and now we have Da'ish."
CNN's Hamdi Alkhshali contributed to this report.
</newstext>
            <videoURLS>
                <url>http://edition.cnn.com/videos/world/2015/06/09/iraq-isis-mosul-anniversary-wedeman-pkg.cnn</url>
                <caption>'Our future, our children, our men have been destroyed' 02:28</caption>
            </videoURLS>
            <videoURLS>
                <url>http://edition.cnn.com/videos/world/2015/06/09/iraq-mosul-one-year-after-fall-isis-karadsheh-lok.cnn</url>
                <caption>One year since Mosul fell to ISIS 02:16</caption>
            </videoURLS>
        </noticia>
    </categoria>
    <categoria tipo="africa">
        <noticia>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/06/17/africa/the-king-with-100-wives-cameroon/index.html</url>
            <titulo>The king with 100 wives</titulo>
            <date>2015-06-17T10:14:21Z</date>
            <author>By Eliza Anyangwe, Soni Methu and Colin Hancock, for CNN</author>
            <newstext>(CNN)Abumbi II, the 11th fon, or king, of Bafut, Cameroon, has close to 100 wives. They weren't all his to start. According to local tradition, when a fon dies, his successor inherits all his wives and then marries his own queens.
"The queens have a great role to play in the fondom," notes Prince Nickson, also of Bafut, noting that it is up to these women behind the man to shape him in his kingly role.
"Behind every successful man must be a very successful, staunch woman," says Abumbi's third wife, Queen Constance.
"Our tradition has it that when you are king, the elderly wives remain to hand down the tradition to the younger wives, and also to teach the king the tradition because the king had been a prince, not a king."
Despite the fact that polygamy is legal in Cameroon, the data shows that there are far fewer polygamous marriages across the African continent. The practice is being challenged by changing values, the spread of the Christian faith, the growing appeal of the western way of life but also the rising costs of having large families. It is against this backdrop that Cameroon's traditional rulers must walk the fine line between two often conflicting cultures.
"During colonialism other values came in, of governance, different from the traditional values we had and therefore there is this constant conflict between the traditional values and modern western values," admits Fon Abumbi II, who has ruled Bafut, the largest fondom in the region, for 47 years.
"My role is to blend them, to find the way forward so my subjects can enjoy the fruits of development and modernity without destroying their culture. Without a culture, you are not a human being, you are an animal. And therefore the chieftaincy institution is the guarantor of our culture."
Though polygamy is often met with criticism in the West, there are some who deem it a valuable tradition. After meeting with Fon Abumbi II, Soni Methu, presenter for CNN's Inside Africa, noted that there was more to the practice than meets the eye:
"I understand that we might be quick to judge the lifestyle of the kings, but just like in the United Kingdom, African kingdoms and kings are bound to a rich culture and history. (Practices) like inheritance of all your father's wives is nothing but a moral obligation."
She also observed that many of these royals are highly accomplished. On meeting the queens of Fon Ndofua Zofia II of Babungo -- one of Cameroon's youngest traditional rulers -- Methu said:
"All his young wives, forced on him by tradition, spoke fluent English in a French-speaking region and were great marketers."
It is this seeming contradiction that makes life in the fondom fascinating and confusing. Are they stuck in the past or keeping pace with the present? Fon Zofoa III doesn't think you have to choose. He may have "inherited" 72 wives and more than 500 children after his father's death, but he considers himself a very modern king.
"To run a kingdom nowadays in this era, you must be educated because things are moving very fast. Like they used to say, education is light, ignorance is darkness."
To meet the fon, or king, of Bafut, as well as his wives, watch the video below:
Read more: Making blockbusters in a nation without cinemas
Read more: The beekeeping women of Cameroon

</newstext>
            <videoURLS>
                <url>http://edition.cnn.com/videos/world/2015/06/08/inside-africa-cameroon-history-b-spc.cnn</url>
                <caption>Dance into the big Babungo Kingdom 07:05</caption>
            </videoURLS>
            <videoURLS>
                <url>http://edition.cnn.com/videos/world/2015/06/08/inside-africa-cameroon-history-a-spc.cnn</url>
                <caption>Bursting with tradition, meet the King of Bafut 08:14</caption>
            </videoURLS>
        </noticia>
        <noticia>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/06/16/africa/freedom-project-smuggler-captain/index.html</url>
            <titulo>Smuggler captain defends trafficking</titulo>
            <highlights>CNN Freedom Project investigates human trafficking route from Africa to Europe</highlights>
            <highlights>Smuggler boat captain defends his role and blames the parents of trafficked children</highlights>
            <date>2015-06-16T18:03:10Z</date>
            <author>Nima Elbagir, CNN</author>
            <newstext>Burj Mughayzil, Egypt (CNN)On a sandy beach in one of the many inlets dotting Egypt's Mediterranean coastline two men are standing off to one side watching us interview families whose children have been trafficked into Europe. Eventually the taller of them begins to jump in.
He starts shouting and explaining why he works on the smuggler boats carrying the human cargo into Europe. "What does the government do for us? We're fishermen but there's nothing to catch."
The village, Burj Mughayzil, is essentially a smugglers' village. By their own count 2,000 young men and boys have disappeared. Some as young as 11 and 12, they are lured by the European dream -- but so many of them either end up in Italian jails accused of crewing the smuggling ships or killed in the crossing.
We were hoping somewhere on the beach to find a crewman on a smuggling ship, someone who had made the journey and returned. We found two; the tall man and his slimmer friend, who told us they were a ship's mate and a captain.
When I asked if they'd talk on camera they agreed. To our surprise they both asked to show their faces and to give their names.
CNN has retraced the route traveled by the children from small villages on Egypt's Mediterranean coast, across the sea to Sicily by boat, then making their way to the Italian capital, Rome, where they fall victim to drug and prostitution rings. Thousands of children are risking their lives, falling prey to traffickers, for the dream of a better future for them and their families.
Captain Mahmoud and Mohammed told us: "We work the ships. Me and a crew of 15 people. If the [Egyptian] government was helping us in any way we wouldn't be crossing in any way."
The trips can take up to nine days on the open seas. The Egyptian Government says it has increased its vigilance along the coastline but still the smugglers are finding ways out.
Sometimes he says, 20 boys are crammed on a tiny fishing boat fitted with an onboard motor, so they can be brought out to sea where he and his crew wait on a bigger boat which holds up to 600 people.
'It's risky for the boat and for everyone on it. We could be sentenced to 25 years or be executed if anything happens, God forbid, to anyone on board if it becomes a death trip."
He also risks years in an Italian jail on the other side and a 15,000 euro ($17,000) fine for every single person on board. The fine can stretch into the millions, Italian authorities say.
It's a risk he knowingly takes. Though, the captain says, leaving him and his men "to rot in jail," is not the solution.
"There are big fish and there are small fish. The small fish are the ones who are in Italian jails. The big fish live freely here in Egypt, freely in Italy."
Many of the parents claim it is the children themselves who want to go -- but teens we spoke to in Italy say their families expect them to work once they get to Europe and to send money home. Others admit Europe is seen as a way of earning the family much-needed cash but they say they didn't know about the trafficker gangs behind the smuggling routes. Yet others say they were deceived by the smugglers who make empty promises of opportunity across the Med. Authorities in both countries are clear, they say the parents are guilty -- at the very least -- of abandoning their children.
The smugglers, Captain Mahmoud says, are very brazen.
"We leave here at dusk, dawn, whenever. It doesn't matter if you know you are risking jail anyway. We'll have been paid -- us and the crew - 10,000 Egyptian pounds ($1,300) each. That feeds a crewman's family and kids for a month. Then after that, who knows? Risk it again or die of hunger."
Egyptian minors have been flooding into Italy by the thousands according to the Italian Ministry of Labor, taking advantage of Italian laws that grant state protection to those under 18 who arrive in Italy unaccompanied. It's not just the passengers that are underage though; his crew often is as well. Captain Mahmoud says they are pressured by their families.
"People here in this village, they're selling their kids. They think, 'we're 10 [people] and we can't find enough to eat. When we're nine, we can eat a little better. If we're eight, we can eat even better still. If two get locked up? Better than we all die together.' All the people in Italian jails? They're the victims of the parents here who can't afford to eat."
I asked if they felt a responsibility for the people making the crossing, for those who have died.
"How can we not?" he said. "If anything happens to them, it happens to us. If the ship sinks we drown together."
His tall friend, Mohammed, talks over him, "How can we not be sad? These are our cousins, our brothers. I still see their faces."
At the end of the interview Captain Mahmoud asks again if we're going to broadcast this, if his government will see this. I tell him, yes, we will. Good, he says. Let them hear the truth.
Dominique Van Heerden, Luca Muzi, Sara Sirgany and Mohamed Kazaz contributed to this report.
</newstext>
            <videoURLS>
                <url>http://edition.cnn.com/videos/world/2015/06/16/pkg-elbagir-migrants-sicily-amanpour.cnn</url>
                <caption>Egypt teens seek roads paved with gold in Europe 05:23</caption>
            </videoURLS>
            <videoURLS>
                <url>http://edition.cnn.com/videos/world/2015/06/15/elbagir-freedom-project-young-men-gone.cnn</url>
                <caption>Where have all the young men gone? 05:00</caption>
            </videoURLS>
        </noticia>
        <noticia>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/05/19/africa/namibia-rhino-hunt/index.html</url>
            <titulo>Texas hunter bags his rhino on controversial hunt in Namibia</titulo>
            <date>2015-05-21T20:28:08Z</date>
            <author>By Ed Lavandera, CNN</author>
            <newstext>Northern Namibia (CNN)In January 2014, Corey Knowlton bid $350,000 for a permit to hunt and kill a black rhino in Namibia.
He won the permit and became a target himself.
The hunt is now complete. A rhino is dead.
This is how it happened.

Windhoek, Namibia -- Knowlton arrived quietly in Namibia to hunt the famed black rhino.
Nearly 18 months ago, the Texas hunter bid $350,000 to kill a black rhinoceros in the southern African country of Namibia. The permit was issued by Namibia's Ministry of Environment and Tourism and auctioned by the Dallas Safari Club.
Since then, Knowlton has faced scathing criticism and death threats as the world reacted to the controversial hunt of one of the world's most endangered species. Knowlton has spent the last year and a half preparing and planning the hunt that is being highly scrutinized by animal welfare groups around the world.
He agreed to let our CNN crew document the hunt.
"At this point, the whole world knows about this hunt and I think it's extremely important that people know it's going down the right way, in the most scientific way that it can possibly happen," Knowlton said after arriving in Africa.
Knowlton, 36, from Dallas, wants the world to see that the hunt of such a majestic beast on the African continent is not the work of a bloodthirsty American hunter but a vital component of Namibia's effort to save the animal from extinction.
Knowlton's $350,000 will go to fund government anti-poaching efforts across the country. And the killing of an older rhino bull, which no longer contributes to the gene pool but which could harm or kill younger males, is part of the science of conservation, he argues.
That's why he says he's doing more to save the black rhino than his critics, and why he wanted us along on this historic hunt.
Opponents like the International Fund for Animal Welfare have not been swayed, saying hunting as conservation is a bankrupt notion. "We'll simply never agree with that," fund director Azzedine Downes said. "There's a lot of other things that we can and must do in order to protect these animals."
The journey of this hunt will examine the emotional debate raging around the issue of how best to protect endangered species on a continent that is home to some of the most legendary animals on the planet.
"I think people have a problem just with the fact that I like to hunt," Knowlton said. "I want to see the black rhino as abundant as it can be. I believe in the survival of the species."

Northern Namibia -- The hunt sets off with a sunrise flight to the region of Namibia where Knowlton will track a black rhino.
There's a great deal of concern about news coverage of the hunt in Namibia. We've been told that when our reports are broadcast around the world that Namibian government officials fear poaching syndicates will use the information to identify the location of other black rhinos.
For that reason, we have agreed not to report the specific locations of the hunt. According to animal conservationists, there are approximately 5,000 black rhinos in the wild worldwide today, 2,000 of them in Namibia.
Hentie van Heerden is a professional hunter hired by the Namibian government to guide Knowlton on the highly scrutinized hunt of the black rhino.
Van Heerden, 40, has an international clientele, mostly from Europe, who come to hunt wild game and the exotic animals of Africa.
He was born in Namibia and grew up hunting. The thorn-infested terrain in the north of the country does not faze him. He wears sandals even when he hunts the wildest of animals.
The bearded van Heerden has the dry sense of humor of a skilled hunter teaching a journalist what to do if we are to stare down a charging rhino.
"The aim is to get out of its way without him flattening you," he said. "It's very rare that they come back for seconds and if that is the case, you have to get some more out of its way."
Van Heerden says there are a few critics of the black rhino hunt in Namibia, but most people here embrace a culture of hunting.
"There will always be activists and that's how they make their money," he said. "They have no clout here in Namibia, because people understand hunting."
The hunt is sanctioned and monitored by Namibia's Ministry of Environment and Tourism. It has identified 18 black rhinos across the country that meet the criteria for being hunted and eliminated.
The rhino must be an older rhino that is no longer reproducing and is considered a threat to younger, healthier rhinos.
Rhinos are intensely territorial and will often kill each other in gruesome fights.
Knowlton is targeting one of four black rhinos at the top of the government list, the ones considered "high priority threats to the herd."
But identifying these rhinos in the dense brush and in the heat of a dangerous hunt makes Knowlton uneasy, though he will have the help of local trackers and guides.
"If it charges at us and we are already sure it's the right one, we are going to kill it," Knowlton said. "If we aren't sure if it's the right one, we are going to try and get out of the way. If we don't feel like we can get out of the way, we got to kill it."
That would be the worst-case scenario for Knowlton. For him, the rhino hunt must be carried out flawlessly.

Northern Namibia -- Just after sunrise, Knowlton arrives at a watering hole hidden deep in the Namibian brush to start the hunt. Two government trackers have spotted signs of a rhino heading away from the water.
The footprint appears fresh. The weathered wrinkles of the rhino's hide are still visible in the print. The intricate details in the sand suggest the tracks are just a few hours old.
The government tracker says, based on the footprints, he can tell this animal is probably one of the black rhinos Knowlton has been permitted to hunt, and that the animal is probably no more than 5 miles away.
This is where the hunt begins.
The trackers move quickly through the thorny bush and tall grasses. They rarely speak. Quick hand signals are all they need to show the path to follow.
Silence is vital when you're tracking a black rhino.
The hunting party winds its way through the brush. The rhino's footprints suggests the nearly 3,000 pound (1,360 kilogram) beast is meandering, which tells the hunters it does not feel threatened.
As the heat of the day intensifies, rhinos will usually find shady areas to take quick naps.
The ranger from the ministry who is observing and leading the trackers says the hunting party is gaining ground on the rhino.
But the brush is so dense. Knowlton worries that we could stumble across the rhino at any moment and end up face to face.
"I think people think of it as this docile thing," Knowlton said of his prey. "But you are dealing with an extremely athletic animal that can do whatever it wants to you very quickly."
The only sounds are the brushes and scrapes of the hunting party cutting through the thorn-infested bushes of this terrain. It seems like every bush has wicked thorns that rip across our skin and clothing.
Rhinos have an intense sense of smell and hearing that alerts them to danger from hundreds of yards away. The winds are swirling in the early afternoon hours and the tracker says the rhino can probably sense our presence and is moving away quickly.
Knowlton is more concerned with something else. He's been told there are three rhinos known to inhabit the area he's in, but the Namibian government has only authorized the hunting of two of them.
Visibility in the brush around us is down to about 15 feet (4.6 meters.) Knowlton is worried that if the rhino charges through the thick brush that he would only have a split second to decide whether to take the shot.
It's becoming too risky. We've spent five hours trekking nearly 6 miles through the brush when Knowlton and his hunting partner decide to call it a day.
Killing the wrong rhino, Knowlton said, would be a catastrophic mistake.
Last year, one of Knowlton's critics suggested the trophy hunting of a black rhino was like shooting a couch in a living room.
This criticism annoys Knowlton endlessly. He's quick to bring it up with a heavy dose of sarcasm.
"So this is just like hunting a couch? Give me a break," he said. "This isn't easy. It's brutal."

On the road to southern Namibia -- Knowlton decides the hunt in the north is too treacherous. The brush is dense and visibility low.
That's a dangerous combination for the hunting party and Knowlton knows that killing the wrong rhino will make him an even bigger target of international outrage.
He and his hunting guide decide to drive to southern Namibia to target another dangerous black rhino that lives in a region with better visibility.
But on the way we hear that rhino has died, probably of natural causes.

Northern Namibia -- Knowlton returns to the region that makes him the most nervous. And on this morning, the trails are not strong.
The trackers have trouble finding prints leading away from the watering holes where the rhinos drink vast amounts of water.
It's clear the rhino hunt will not end today.

Northern Namibia -- The morning starts with a startling discovery. Knowlton's professional hunting guide has discovered a camera image showing a rhino at a remote watering hole just before sunrise.
The image is stunning. The rhino is more massive than I expected. Its horn is long with a lethal pointed tip. Knowlton spots a large gash in the rhino's ear. It's a crucial identifying mark that tells him instantly this rhino is on the approved government list to be hunted.
The hunting party quickly picks up the tracks and disappears into the vicious African bush.
The rhino footprints are fresh and light on the sand, telling the trackers the animal is slowly walking, eating grass and taking naps in the shade to avoid the rising sun.
Today feels different. There's a sense that just beyond our view we are close to the rhino. The hunting party stops to drink water in the shade of a tree for 20 minutes.
When the tracking resumes, Knowlton discovers the spot where the rhino had been resting not moments earlier. You can see the imprint of its wrinkled hide still fresh on the sandy ground.
The rhino is close. Knowlton's hands firmly grip his high-powered 500 Nitro Express rifle. Moments later, I see a massive flash of gray leap up over the bushes some 50 feet in front of us. It disappears and you can't tell which direction the rhino is running.
It's jarring to see this close how quickly these massive creatures can move.
I remember the advice van Heerden, the professional hunting guide, gave me the day before.
"You can't outrun the rhino," he said. "If it means to dive into a thorn bush to the left or to the right, we need to get out of its way in a big hurry."
Now we can't see the rhino, but we know it's close.
Van Heerden tells Knowlton, "He's angry. The next time he will charge."
Twenty minutes later as the hunting party moves through the brush, I hear a sound I've not heard before during our trek.
The rhino is moving around but it's invisible. It's impossible to grasp how such a beast can move like a ghost in the brush.
The hunting party moves single file through a tree line. As the last member of the group emerges, he looks to his left and no more than 40 feet away the rhino is there, staring straight at us.
"There it is!" says the last member in the group.
It's a breathtaking sight. But this isn't the time to stand and stare. I cut to one side and the rhino starts charging in my direction.
"Ed! Get down!" shouts van Heerden.
I rush behind Knowlton and his hunting guide.
"As soon as you dropped below my gun, I could see the whole animal right behind you," Knowlton would tell me later.
I turn around and for a quick flash only see the top half of the rhino in front of us. Then four shots explode through the air.
The rhino has been hit at least three times.
The hunting party then makes the final push to find the rhino. I've lost track of time. This last push might have taken 30 minutes, it might have taken an hour. It was an incredibly emotional experience.
A tracker climbs into a tree and spots the rhino in an open field about 100 yards away. Knowlton gets into position and fires the final shots. The black rhino is dead.
Knowlton walks up from behind the rhino and when he's certain it's over, he kneels next to it.
"Any time you take an animal's life it's an emotional thing," Knowlton said.
The Namibian government official assures Knowlton it is the rhino on the approved hunting list. The trackers smile with relief and shake hands.
I ask Knowlton if he still feels that killing this black rhino was the right thing to do and that it will benefit the future of this endangered species.
"I felt like from day one it was something benefiting the black rhino," Knowlton reflected just moments after the hunt ended. "Being on this hunt, with the amount of criticism it brought and the amount of praise it brought from both sides, I don't think it could have brought more awareness to the black rhino."
WATCH: Rhino hunter defends killing an endangered animal
READ: Rhino horns more valuable than gold
WATCH: Rhino gets armed guards
WATCH: Getting rhinos back to Uganda
CNN's Jason Morris contributed to this report.
</newstext>
            <image>
                <url>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/150519125557-rhino-corey-knowlton-super-169.jpg</url>
                <caption>Dallas hunter Corey Knowlton paid $350,000 for a rhino-hunting permit, one of three granted per year by the Namibian Ministry of Environment and Tourism.</caption>
            </image>
            <image>
                <url>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/150519125155-rhino-hentie-van-heerden-super-169.jpg</url>
                <caption>Professional hunter Hentie van Heerden had advice if a rhino charges: Get out of its way.</caption>
            </image>
            <image>
                <url>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/150519124521-rhino-footprint-super-169.jpg</url>
                <caption>Prints on the ground are used to track and hunt endangered black rhinos.</caption>
            </image>
            <image>
                <url>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/150519124837-rhino-corey-knowlton-brush-super-169.jpg</url>
                <caption>Hunter Corey Knowlton in the thick, thorny brush of Namibia.</caption>
            </image>
            <image>
                <url>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/150519130015-rhino-trackers-super-169.jpg</url>
                <caption>Trackers search for rhino prints near a watering hole.</caption>
            </image>
            <image>
                <url>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/150519144717-rhino-hunt-super-169.jpg</url>
                <caption>Corey Knowlton, center, with the hunting party.</caption>
            </image>
            <image>
                <url>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/150519130317-rhino-hunted-in-namibia-super-169.jpg</url>
                <caption>The rhino hunted by Corey Knowlton.</caption>
            </image>
            <videoURLS>
                <url>http://edition.cnn.com/videos/world/2015/05/19/erin-dnt-lavandera-namibia-black-rhino-hunt.cnn</url>
            </videoURLS>
        </noticia>
    </categoria>
</jornalType>